I welcome you all to join my lecture.
My name is Zhang Nianhua from North China University.
I'm also a co-owner of the Microgrid Working Group in IEC Standard.
So if you are interested in the Microgrid,
interested in the International Center,
welcome to join our group.
We have already published more than 10 publications for the microwave.
And today, my lecture contains three parts.
The first part is the manufacture of the new power system.
The second one is something about the technical directions for the new type of power system in China.
and the third one is the key application technology for the new power system.
From 2016 to 2020, the Chinese government organized more than 40 experts
to study about the future of the Chinese power and energy development from 2020 until 2060.
And I'm fortunate that I'm one of the experts of the 40 experts.
So I want to report about why China will construct a new power system
and how to build a new power system in the following 30 or 40 years.
So first of all, we study the major features of the new power system in China.
You know that the Chinese government has already issued an objective for the double carbon.
That is, by 2030, we will reach the carbon peak, and by 2060, we will reach carbon neutral.
And also in 2021, the CPC has announced that China will build a new type of power system.
dominated by the renewable energy and this is based on our research we have
already made research about 300 papers of report to the Chinese Department of
Science and Development and also we gave a simple page of the report to the
the city and the city council.
So that based on this technical basement,
the government decided to build a new power system,
new type of power system.
So President Xi has known that China will build
a new power system dominated by the new energy.
What is the new energy?
In China, there are four parts of energies.
Renewable energy, wind, solar, and hydro.
And then after 3.1, there is nuclear.
So the 4 energy, we call new energy.
Renewable energy includes hydro, wind, and solar.
So President Xi announced that he will build a new power system dominated by new energy.
And then the city council has changed this objective to build a new power system with
the proportion of new energy increasing year by year.
Because we don't want the policy to make a misunderstanding of the objective.
because we built a new power system dominated by the new energy until the
2060. So we still have more than 30 years to build a new power system. So first of
all we analyze the main feature of the new power system. We have already
We have already studied our energy features in China, so we summarize that we have three major features in China.
The first feature is that the core dormant energy structure will not change significantly in the short term, in the rest of the 20 years.
You know that maybe 30 years ago, our power generation is generated by the coal-fired power plant.
The proportion is about 30%. That is, 30% of electricity produced is from the coal-fired power plant.
But during the past 20 years, this proportion has reduced to about 50, more than 50.
So we think that the core dormant energy structure will change in the following 30 years.
This is one feature.
Another feature is that the per capita share of energy source in China is relatively low compared with the world average.
The third feature is that the energy, including electricity, including oil, including neutral gas,
the energy is distributed in the reverse direction.
What does the reverse direction mean?
That is, the energy is concentrated in the west part of China.
But the consumption area is the eastern part.
So we have to transport such kind of energy, transport electricity, transport oil and gas from west to east.
So for the electricity production, we have to build a huge electric power network.
For example, use the ultra-high voltage of the transmission network to transmit the electricity from west to east.
So based on the three major features, we study the future of the tiny hour system.
You know that we analyze the energy structure in the world.
So before 1850s, the major, the dominant energy is wood.
The human burns wood to get energy.
But after the first industrial revolution, after 1840s, the steam engine became the domestic energy.
So the domestic energy is corn until the middle of the last century.
The coal, maybe from 1840, increased until the middle of the last century.
And then the coal reduced, gradually reduced.
What is the substitution? The oil.
The oil will substitute the coal to become the domestic energy in the world.
And then, by the beginning of this century, the oil will reduce gradually.
What is the substitution? Neutral gas.
Many experts think that
the first part of this century will be dominated by neutral gas.
But it is not the case in China.
Because China has a lack of neutral gas.
After oil, coal, and oil, the substitution is
renewable energy, solar and hydrogen.
What is solar?
Solar includes wind power, wind solar power, and also means the hydro power.
And the hydrogen is produced by the renewable energies.
So we think that in the first part of this century,
China's energy will be dominated by the renewable energies.
But you can see that this is the percentage occupied of the three kinds of fossil energies.
You know that the European Union and the United States say that neutral gas makes the first one,
and oil makes the second one, and coal makes the third one.
maybe the percentage of the neutral gas is about 40%
and coal, only 20%.
But for China, you can see that China, the majority energy consumption is coal.
So we think that from 2000, maybe to 2030, maybe during the 30 years,
the dormant energy is also coal.
So, working to develop the no fossil energy source
and change the situation that the energy structure is dominated by coal
is our main task.
It's the Chinese government's main task.
So we can see that this is the structure of the United States, Europe, and China.
In the United States, neutral gas occupies about 26%, and the oil occupies about 24%.
For Europe, the oil occupies 40%, and the neutral gas occupies about 25%, and the oil
occupies only 17%.
of China. This figure is collected from the state published data. The oil is 18%, the
neutral gas is about 8%, and coal occupies more than half, that's 57, in 20, maybe 24.
And the second feature of the Chinese energy feature is that the per capita of the energy
is relatively low compared with the world average.
That is, per capita coal is about 30% of the world average.
The per capita oil is only 20% of the world average.
And per capita, neutral gas is 22% of the world's average.
That means that we have to make a policy to save energy, because China is the core of
the world's energy, compared with the huge population.
And third characteristic is that the energy distribution is far from the low center.
we can see that the wind and solar power is concentrated in the solar power farm,
and the wind power farm is concentrated in the northwest China,
in Xinjiang, in Gansu, in Qinghai, and in Inner Mongolia, the west of Inner Mongolia.
And also the coal is concentrated also in the northwest China,
For example, Xinjiang, and Shanxi, and in Mongolia,
they are constructed on coal.
So we have to transform the coal either by electricity,
or by train, or by car, from west to east.
So this is our program.
And for the hydro power, the hydro power is concentrated
in the southwestern of China,
for example in Tibet, in the upstream of the Yangtze River and in Sichuan province.
So we have to transport the hydropower into electricity and then transmit electricity from the west to east.
Because maybe two-thirds of the load concentrated in the east and east part of the country.
and two-thirds of the energy produced is from the West.
So we estimate that about one-third of the electric power
has to be transmitted from the West to the East
by the ultra-high voltage of the transmission network.
So this is our program.
And also for the neutral gas and for the oil, it's also from the West.
The neutral gas, we build a lot of neutral gas pipelines and transmit the neutral gas from Xinjiang, from Sichuan to the East China.
Also from Russia, from Pakistan.
We buy the neutral gas from abroad and then transmit it from west to east to meet the needs of the east countries.
Based on these three features, we have to consider that our new power system has to be built based on the renewable energy, based on the solar and wind.
And also, our electricity generation has to be transmitted from west to east.
So we have to build huge power networks. This is our country's policy.
So, on the generation side, we have to make a clean substitution.
This is very important for the zero-carbon power system.
And we have to make a clean substitution on the production side to build a deep zip-carbon power system.
Because in China, the majority of electricity production is from coal-fired power plants.
So we have to substitute it with wind, solar and hydropower.
But now the hydropower has already developed almost 90%.
So we only left the Tibet and the upstream of the Yangtze River is now undeveloped.
And almost all the hydropower has already developed.
Our power system has three goals. We call it 30, 80 and 90.
What is 30? That is the proportion of the electricity energy consumption will be occupied by more than 30%.
How about north? North is the proportion of the electricity consumption is only 30% in China.
That is that the steel production, the oil production, the transportation, most of the
industrial production is based on the fossil energy, not electricity.
So we have to substitute this kind of industry production from the fossil energy to electricity.
So that by 2060, the percentage of the electric energy consumption in all the industries will
occupy about 70% in China.
This is the first objective, 70.
The second objective is 80.
What is 80?
The proportion of non-fossil energy consumption is more than 80% by 2060.
And how about notice? Notice is only 27%.
And third objective is 90. That is the power electricity generation.
The renewable power generation is about 90%.
That means that our wind power plus solar power plus hydro power and also plus nuclear power.
all together will be occupied by 90% by 2060.
So this is our three goals
of the Chinese energy system production.
So we divided our power system into three generations.
The fourth generation is before 1970s.
That is before the reformation of the Chinese government.
So before the 1970s, we built a primary mode of the Chinese power system.
This power system is very small and independent with each province.
And in the past 50 years, we have built a second generation of the power system.
That is from 1970 to now.
until now. This kind of power system is very modern and very large, a huge power system
that the whole country will make a unique power network. But this kind of power system,
this second generation of power system is highly dependent on fossil energy and it is
unsustainable. It cannot be the Chinese government's double carbon objectives.
That is, by 2030 we reach carbon peak, by 2060 we reach carbon neutral. But this kind of power
system could not meet the needs. So from now on, from the beginning of the
two thousand years we begin to build a new power system that is the third generation
of power system we scheduled that we will use 50 years to build a such a kind of generation
such as the third generation process and the third power system means that the non-for-sale
energy-based power system that is the new power system with the renewable energy as the main body
This is our goal from 20 to now, in the past 20 years.
In the past 20 years, we have built a lot of renewable energy.
We have built a lot of wind farms.
We have built a lot of solar farms in the western of China and also in offshore areas.
So, this is the feature of the three generation of power systems.
The first generation is the small units, and such units, or maybe almost all the units,
is powered by the qualified power plants, and a small percentage, maybe 20%, is from
hydropower.
And the network is low-voltage, about 4,020 kilowatts of the network.
Only connected by each other around the city.
It is an independent power system.
So in the first generation of the power system,
China has built a lot of independent small power systems
and not connected to each other.
And in the past 15 years, we built a second one.
The second generation is large units, large electric power generation units, and the high
voltage and ultra-high voltage transmission lines, and large power grid, we built a large
power grid.
And also, we used a lot of modern technologies, for example, digital technology, the modern
modern communication technology to reform our power system.
So, during the past 50 years, we have built a huge power system with many, many modern technologies.
So that we can create a modern power system.
But this power system is not sustainable.
We have to solve the core problems with the renewable energy.
So we will gradually, we will use 50 years, we will gradually build the third generation
of power system.
And this kind of power system is that the power generation based on renewable energy
and clean energy will be more than 60 to 70%.
This is a major feature of the new power system.
And then we will combine the large scale power plants and we will combine the distributed
power generation.
So nowadays we have built a lot of distributed PV in the consumption in the lower side.
So this is the major feature of the third generation and we schedule to use 50 years
to build such one until 2050.
So, we have analyzed the new power system feature.
What kind of new power system, what kind of the, our current power system will gradually
progress, will gradually turn into a new power system.
So in 2015, the Chinese per capita electricity consumption was only 4,000 kilowatt hours.
That is 10 years ago.
The per capita electricity consumption is only 4,000 kilowatt hours.
But in 2025, the per capita electricity consumption is over 7,000 kilowatt hours.
And by the end of 2025, the average per capita electricity consumption is about 3,500 kilowatt
hours per capita.
So you can see that in the past 10 years, the Chinese electricity consumption will increase
very fast, almost double.
But this is not enough.
We have forecast about the future, maybe by 2050, what is the per capita electricity consumption.
We have argued a lot, we have discussed with many experts during our planning for the future Chinese power plants.
So the final conclusion is that Chinese per capita electricity consumption by 2050 will be 11,500 kilowatt hours.
That is our estimation.
That means that from now on, our total consumption of electricity power will also be doubled.
And this double electric power generation is mainly produced by the wind and solar power by the renewable energy.
And also the remaining, our remaining electric power generation, maybe the main body is the coal-fired power plant,
will gradually substitute by the renewable energy.
So that is a very heavy task for the Chinese government, to build the renewable energy to substitute the coal-fired power plants.
Why? Why we have so high of the electricity consumption?
Because the first one is that, we mean the first 70%, that is the electric power consumption.
In every industry, we occupy about 70% of the whole energy consumption.
From now, this is only 30%.
So there will be a lot of electricity production that will be required.
This is one reason.
Another reason is the urbanization of China.
A lot of people from the countryside to the urban.
So the average per capita consumption of electricity will increase very fast.
This is the two reasons that we estimate that the average per capita electricity consumption will be 11,500 kWh.
So this is our estimation.
So the total electricity growth from 2020 is only 7.5 trillion, and until 2060, it is 17 trillion kilowatt hours.
And this is our estimation in 2020. Before we gave our report to the CBC, we made an estimation of 17 trillion kilowatt hours.
But nowadays, we think that this figure is not enough.
So, from the calculation comes that it is estimated that by 2060, the total electricity consumption will exceed 23.1 pounds.
Because there is a new situation, for example digital, the AI, the electricity consumption will increase.
So we estimate that the total electricity consumption by 2060 will be more than 20 trillion kilowatt hours.
This is a very huge electricity production.
And this huge electricity production, maybe the most percentage of this electricity generation,
will be produced by the wind power and solar power.
So this is our requirement, and also our situation.
We have to face these difficulties to build so many renewable energies,
to meet the needs of the so high electricity consumption requirements.
So this is our estimation.
Another feature is that the AI and data center
has become a new global driver of the electricity growth.
Not only in China, but also all over the world, AI and digital centers will require more and more electric power.
For example, last year, we visited Germany.
The German experts think that the GPU, each chip of the GPU, consumes electric power of about 1000 HW, or 1500 HW per chip.
But, by 2027, the average chip of the GPU will consume the electric power will be more than 3,000 kilowatts.
So we think that the digital economy is driving in the surge of computing power demand.
And data center will expand very fast, both in scale and in rock numbers.
This is our situation.
And both computing equipment operation and the cooling energy consumption required,
both of these two kinds of energies are very high, requirement is very high.
It's running continuously about 24 hours in one day.
So the cooling system account maybe about 30% to 40% of the total energy consumption.
And also, the energy consumption for data storage and processing will also gradually increase.
It's about 20%.
So the increased requirements of the electricity consumption requirements for the total work is about, before 2030, will be about 4%.
So that the whole world will increase their total electricity consumption by 4% until 2030.
So we have already encountered that shortage of the electric power transportation, electric power transmission stations,
short of the equipment.
In Japan, they want to build several digital centers,
but if they book the transformers from ABB, from Senegal,
the data, the interruption data is about three years.
They have to wait three years for the transformer to be produced.
But they have to transfer to the mainland of China.
The mainland of China, the transformer production period is only three months.
So many Japan enterprises, they build the storage stations, they build data centers,
and they have to purchase some equipment from China.
So this is the situation.
The second feature of the Chinese power system is that our new energy power generation will
develop very fast.
In the past 25 years, the solar power generation and the wind power generation, the capacitor
is increased about 150 times during the past 25 years.
So we think that this rapidly increase will continue until 2045.
And not only the installed capacity of the power generation for the centralized wind and PV power generation,
but also the distributed PV is also increasingly fast in the eastern part of China.
For example, in Shandong province, in the eastern province in Shandong, the installed
capacity of the distributed PV reached to nearly 60 gigawatts, and this kind of
60 gigawatts is almost equal to the load requirements. So we have to
trade a lot of distributed PV to be connected to the networks. So this is
also our operation, a very difficult operation for the new power system.
So this is our forecast for the Chinese generation, for the Chinese power capacity
And in 2025, the total installed power capacity will reach to 3.4 billion kilowatts.
And in this generation capacity, the wind power accounts for about 640 million.
And the solar power is 1.2 billion kilowatts.
So the wind plus solar power make up about nearly half of the total power capacity.
But you can see the generation. The solar and wind power generation is only maybe 21%.
Because the operation time per year for the wind and solar power is only maybe 2000 hours.
But for the coal-fired power plants, it is more than 5,000 hours.
So that we use a lot of capacity, but the generation proportion is relatively low.
So we cannot call this kind of power system as a new power system.
It is not a new kind of power system, because it is not dominated by the renewable energy.
So by 2030, the total installed power capacity will reach to 5.4 billion kilowatts,
and include 3.4 billion kilowatts from clean energy, from solar, from wind power, from hydro and from nuclear.
And the solar and the wind power is on account, the capacity is on account more than half of the total capacity.
But the power generation, by 2030, the power generation will be 13 trillion kilowatt hours.
The non-fossil energy account is only half, and the wind and solar power account is more than 30%.
So this is our situation.
So in the next five years, we cannot see that we have already completed the new power system.
We still have another 10 or 15 years to build a new power system.
So this is our situation.
I have deleted a lot of pictures because we have forecast the power generation capacity
and power generation by 2050s and 2060s, but I think this future will change a lot.
So I did not leave the future there.
And the third feature is that the safety program.
Because we have interconnected a lot of solar and wind power,
so the power system is not stable.
It's fluctuating.
So the structure of the power grid is becoming increasingly complex.
But the threat from the neutral disaster
and the risk of the cyber attack from the external,
internal, from the outside, increases.
So we have to make a safety prevention and an emergency response.
We have to use our power systems with urgent need to improve the capacity of the emergency
response.
For example, in 2006, the central China power grid encountered a vibration, a big vibration.
So this is a very deep lesson for Chinese power grid.
So every lecture includes this because of the misoperation of the protection.
For example, in Hainan province, Hainan province has encountered two weather attacks, typhoons.
In 2005, a big typhoon attacked Hainan.
And the year before last, in 2024, there was also a big typhoon attack across the Hainan province, and almost all the distribution network was destroyed.
And also in 2008, there is a heavy snow and the freezing rain caused severe damage for the power grid in more than 10 provinces along the Yangtze River.
And many steel towers have already collapsed.
So the weather, the neutral disasters will destroy, will make many risks for the new power system.
And as another picture, the proportion of electricity received outside the urban cities will increase year by year.
For example, in Beijing, maybe in 2000, more than 70% of the electric power generation is from inside Beijing.
from inside Beijing. But nowadays, a lot of electric power plants will move to Shanxi, to Inner Mongolia.
They move outside Beijing because of the environmental problem and so on.
So nowadays, only 20% of the power generation is inside Beijing.
and almost more than 80% electricity is from outside.
So this caused a main problem of the voltage, a voltage problem,
as the Beijing electric power grid lacked a base.
So the voltage from outside Beijing into the central Beijing,
the voltage gradually goes lower and lower.
So the reactive power becomes the insurgency.
So this is another problem.
So this is the situation.
Another situation is the load characteristics.
The load characteristics become more and more dynamic, sensitive,
because we have already interrupted the power electronics.
We use a lot of power electronic devices into the power grid.
So that makes the load characteristics from the resistance constant load to the power
constant load.
That is the load received from the network.
The load received the network gradually becomes constant as the voltage fluctuates, but the
the power has not changed.
So this is not a good problem.
This is a very high-tech problem.
So we have to make the voltage balance.
This is another situation.
And the more and more electric power,
power electronics leads to decrease the system initial
because many qualified power plants will quit the operation
or reduce their reductions.
So the system initial becomes lower and lower.
So we have to encounter many difficulties
for the operation of such a huge, such a complex power system.
So this is another situation.
That is how we can respond to the change in the new energy
and lower the capacity.
So more and more percentage of the renewable energies to be interconnected into the power system.
And how can we respond to the change?
And how can we prevent the large-scale power outage?
How can we get against the cyber attacks?
And how can we ensure the safety and the stable operation of the increasingly complex house?
So this is our, we have encountered many difficulties to run, to operate such a complex power system.
So this is another feature of the new power system.
That's the user's demand for the power supply reliability and power quality increase.
We have compared with the Singapore and Japan.
The Chinese power reliability is only 99.9%.
That means that every year the average voltage of the electric power is about 5 hours in China,
including countryside and urban. The average voltage is 5 hours.
But you can see in Singapore, 99.9999.
That means the only half-minute outage in the whole Singapore bridge.
In Japan, it's 99.999.
We call it five nines.
So the outage is only two minutes.
So this is the situation of the Chinese power system.
So we have to increase the power availability
to meet the increasing requirements of the lower requirements.
And there is an estimation that in the United States,
the United States users, they have estimated that
the reliability requirements,
high reliability requirements of the users,
the percentage is only less than 10% nowadays.
But in the last 30 years, maybe more than 60% of the users will require a very high reliability like Singapore.
Because more and more loads are very sensitive to the electro-power reliability.
How to increase the reliability?
We have to make the distribution network to transfer the distribution network.
For the main cities in China, the distribution network is a ring network structure,
but it is operated in a bridge region.
So there is only one source from one 10 kilobytes of distribution network.
But for Paris, for central London, for Tokyo, for Singapore, there is a ring network for distribution.
So this is one reason why the reliability of distribution is quite high.
Because of the structure of distribution network.
So this means that we have to invest a lot of money to increase the reliability in the Chinese distribution network.
So in the next five years' plan, maybe more than half of the investment from the state grid will be paid,
will be invested to the distribution network. So this is why we have to increase the reliability.
Another reason, another measure to increase the variability is that we have to make the table.
The table is very light, but nowadays a lot of overhead lines have to be replaced by the table.
And we have to build a lot of distribution automation devices to make the automation level.
And also our management is relatively rough, so that this is the distance between developed countries and China.
So we have to invest a lot of money to increase the distribution of utilities,
so that to catch up with the developed countries.
So, compared with the developed countries, there is still a significant gap in the power
reliability.
So, we have to deal with that.
Another thing is the power quality.
We have already defined five indexes of power quality.
The one is the voltage level.
Another is the frequency.
The third one is harmonic.
The fourth one is the three-phase unbalance, and the last one is the voltage dip, or which voltage dip.
So, in these five indexes, the first two, the voltage and the frequency,
will be examed to the electrical power utility and the power plant.
We have a very strict, we have a very strict for the voltage and frequency, and for the
surface unbalance, and for the harmonics, in China, we have already changed a lot.
But it's very high tech of the problem is the voltage deep.
What is voltage deep?
That is, there is a busbar, and one busbar, there will be a lot of middle voltage of the distribution lines.
And if there is a fault in one line, if there is a fault in one line,
And the load connected over the busbar will encounter a voltage drop.
And after several seconds, after a short time, the protection device cut off the fault and the voltage resumed.
all the lower the voltage will be reduced, so there is a very very short time of the
voltage set, but such kind of voltage set is not affected in the ordinary load, but it
will affect the sensitive load, for example the cheap production, the cheap
manufacturer. It is a very very difficult. I have discussed with the president of
the Singapore Power Grid. I asked him that how about your reliability?
Why do you not still increase your reliability from maybe half minutes to a shorter time?
he said that we have very, very, very, very difficult because Singapore has two transmission
lines to Malaysia, two transmission lines, 110 kilowatt transmission lines. And in Malaysia,
there are a lot of short circuits. And if there is a short circuit, Singapore will feel
So the half minutes of the audit is from the electric power quality.
I think some of you are from Malaysia.
Really? I don't know.
I asked the Singapore president of the Singapore National Power Grid.
Maybe because of the imbalance of power need and supply.
Yeah, there are two traffic lines from Singapore to Malaysia.
And then Malaysia take from Thailand as well.
Yeah. But in Malaysia, every year, occasionally there are short circuits.
If there is a short circuit in Singapore, the whole power system will fail and affect a lot of industry.
So how we can meet the users ever increasing demand for power supply,
and power quality, especially for the voltage deal.
So this is our, we have encountered a very serious problem.
The fifth feature is that the power electronics in the power system will increase very fast.
because that's the power electronic device. For example, the Soligen Carbide and other advanced chip devices
become very cheap, become very popular, the capacity and the reverse voltage become very low.
And also, we have to build many flexible DC transmission lines.
This means that we need a lot of power electronic devices to be interconnected in the power system.
And also for the wind, for the solar, for the renewable energy generation,
we have to use power electronics to connect the wind farm, to connect the PV farm into the power system.
Also we use a lot of power electronic devices.
And for the storage, the storage has to be transferred, the DC storage current has to be transferred to the AC and we use power electronics.
And data center, they use a lot of power electronic devices.
And for the enterprises, there are a lot of production lines, they use the speed adjust, they use the power electronic to adjust the speed.
So that this huge power system will include a lot of power electronics.
This means that the power electronics will control very fast.
So there's no initial.
So this could not give you any time to adjust the system because it is adjusted very fast.
So this is another problem.
The power system initial becomes lower and lower.
So we need to balance, to adjust the electric power generation and the power consumption.
We have to adjust to make a balance.
So this is quite difficult for the Chinese competitors.
So the sixth one is that the energy storage has become a very important man to support the new power system.
Because we have less initials, we have less adjustments, the qualified power plant gradually quits from the power system.
So we need a lot of storage. Not only the pump storage, we build a lot of pump storage in China for the southern grid or the state grid.
We build a lot of storage.
We estimate that by 2050, the pumped storage capacity will be doubled compared with 2025.
Will be doubled.
But it's not enough.
The requirement of the storage is larger and larger compared with the pumped storage.
So we have to build a lot of chemical batteries for power storage.
We have to build a lot of flow batteries.
We have to build a lot of air-compressed energy storage to make the balance between the load and the source.
So this is another problem. We have to pay a lot of money to build the storage.
So, the seventh feature is that there is an increased regulation need at both ends of the power system.
Because by the source end, we have built a lot of wind and power farms, so we need regulation.
We need storage directly.
And also, in the lower side, we have a lot of distributed PV.
This also needs to adjust.
So the initial power system decreases, the regulation demand increases.
This is the value.
Another feature is that the distribution system is connected to a large amount of distributed PV.
So, this distributed PV, put up in the 12 o'clock, the distributed PV, the total amount
of distributed PV generation is larger than the load required.
So in Shandong, in Zhejiang, in this province, in the noon, around the 12 o'clock, the tariff,
the battery of the electric battery becomes very low to accelerate the consumption of the distributed TVs.
So this also requires adjustments.
And the third reason is the electric market.
China will build a full electric market by 2030.
maybe last month, last month, the council issued a document to build an electric market,
a whole electric market in China.
So the electric market needs more and more very precise interaction between the lower and the south.
So it also requires some storage, some adjustments.
So we can see that renewable energies are being used by optical allocation and efficient
production, and the flexible regulation capacity of the grid is intense, and continues improving
the market mechanisms through the interaction and coordination of the source, grid, load,
and storage.
So this is our very heavy task.
And also to diversify the market transactions, maybe in the following 5 or 10 years, the market transactions will become very complex.
And this way we can target continuously, so stimulate the enterprise to encourage user
to participate in the accelerated service, for example the frequent adjustment, for example
the peak load adjustment.
And then we will transcend the coordination, regulation of the source with load.
So this is a very difficult task.
And this is why we have to build a new type of power system.
From the national policy point of view, we have to reach to the double carbon.
We have to reach the carbon neutral by 2060.
So the national strategy is to control the total amount of the fossil energy.
We have to improve the energy utilization efficiency because we are very poor for the energy portal.
We have to implement the renewable energy substitutions.
We have to deepen the power market reforms.
We have to build a new power system dominated by the new energy, especially for the renewable energy,
to achieve the strategic goals of the carbon peak by 2030 and to achieve the carbon neutrality by 2060.
So this is a necessity from the government.
Another one, we have discussed a lot of feasibilities, how we can operate such a kind of system.
So from the technology point of view, there are a lot of innovative technologies
such as artificial intelligence, such as big data processing, such as the Internet of Things,
have promoted the efficiency and reasonable consumption of renewable energy.
So, there are various kinds of energies, such as electric cooling, heating,
have shown the different coupling characteristics with electricity.
So we have to make a head, core, and other energies together to consider the balance
of the power system.
So this is the feasibility we have discussed in many technologies, how to operate such
a complex system.
So we think that it is feasible to operate such a complex system to meet the necessary
necessary needs of the carbon neutralization.
So this is why we have to build power systems.
So we can enter into the second part,
the technical direction.
We use what kind of technology to operate,
to build such a huge, such a complex power system.
And the power system can express these new features
features that is efficient assumption of higher proportion of the new energy will increase
the regulation demand at both end of the power system this is one difficult another with a large
amount of power electronic devices is widely accessible lead to a decline in the system
initial so we need a lot of storage we need a lot of adjustments another one is that the continuous
growth in the load, you know, the load requirement will be doubled in the next 30 years.
The continuous growth of load and demand of the high quality of pasta pie for the reliability,
for the quality from users have raised the high requirement for the planning, for the
construction, for the operation, for the digital transformation of the distribution network.
So our large investment will be concentrated in the distribution network in the next five years' time.
And that the conventional qualified power plants will gradually be free-stopped.
That is another very difficult one, that there will be lack of adjustment.
So it challenges the system's stability and balancing capabilities.
So we have to focus on the forward-looking and the directional innovation technologies.
Such kind of technologies will support the new power system operation and the power system planning in the next 10 to 20 years.
So we have to think that what kind of technology will maintain the operations,
the stable operation of the power system.
So I think that one important technology is TI.
The artificial intelligence and the big data application
will become a very strong support for the new kind of power system.
We have discussed with dispatcher from the national state grid,
In 2018, we planned a future power system.
We think that in the future, maybe in the next 50 years,
maybe more than half of the electric power generation comes from the renewable energy.
But the dispatcher thinks that no, it's not possible.
Because nowadays, in 2018, the state grid has encountered maybe more than 15% of the renewable energy.
And they have seen that it is very difficult to operate such a high percentage of the renewable energy.
But if in the future, in the next 30 years, we build more and more renewable energy,
We built maybe more than 50% of the renewable energy to be interconnected into the power system.
How about it? They think that it's impossible.
And then we invited a lot of AI experts.
Some AI experts think that it is possible. Why?
Because in Chinese dependent center, every 15 minutes, we calculate operation feature modes.
We have calculated. We have made one adjustment just every 15 minutes.
Every 15 minutes, we calculate the whole power system operation mode,
and then we order adjustment orders to the power plants to adjust their output,
to adjust their voltage, to meet the fluctuation of the load.
So this is the traditional dispatching system.
But it does not meet the requirements of the new power system.
Because every 15 minutes the weather changes a lot.
So the output of the wind power and the output of the solar power changes a lot.
So it is not possible to make the dispatching order every 15 minutes.
So the AI experts think that how about for the whole complex of our system, we issue a balance over every minute, every one minute, or every one second.
So using the AI, using the big data, we can reach such a goal that we make adjustments every second.
If we can make adjustments every second, we can make a balance of the high percentage of renewability.
So we think that the RIM, the AI technology, is the enhancer of the agency's completion.
So based on such artificial technologies, we can make the reform of the dispatch center.
We can make a very precise model for the calculation of the whole power network.
We can make a very precise conclusion of the adjustment every second or every millisecond.
So that can meet the needs of the future new power system.
So the intelligent agent of the power system dispatching will change the new power system control and change the operation of the power system.
For example, the overall monitoring agent, the situation awareness agent, the collaborative control agent, the decision assistance agent.
All of this we use the AI technology to make the balance, to make the stable operation of the power.
Okay, there are a lot of applications.
So we think that AI artificial applications will be the strong support for the new power system.
This is the one directional technology.
And using the AI system, we have to make application of the big data.
So there's a very, very huge data collected from the power system, from every department of power system.
We have to combine the data to make a database to support the AI application.
So this is the one direction, the smart way.
Another direction is that the efficient high density and low cost and long life of energy storage.
Not only the pump storage, but also the grid forming energy storage, not the grid falling.
The grid falling storage is only for the users, for the customers, to make money, to make a preference for their adjustment.
and the power grid, the power system needs good forming energy storage.
They can adjust the reactive power, they can adjust the quality of the power supply,
they can adjust so many things.
And the third direction is that the high reliability and low loss of power electronic devices.
Because a lot of PV, a lot of wind power needs high efficiency of power electronic
And the fourth directional technology is high efficiency and low cost of solar and wind power generation.
We have developed a lot of new materials to make the efficiency of the PV transformation higher and higher.
Maybe from 20% to 30% or more than 30%.
And also, we make the off-shell and on-shell wind power.
The wind power, the one generation side of the wind power becomes larger and larger.
In the past 20 years, we built a lot of small 1.5 megawatts of the wind power.
But nowadays, this wind power is already replaced by 5 megawatts, by 6 megawatts.
So this is another technology.
And then, we think that advanced transmission technology, for example, the flexible DC transmission, will be built to transport the electricity from the west to the east.
So this is also another direction of the technology.
Also, I have to make you a notice that the small-scale and the safety nuclear power station is also a very bright future,
especially in the United States.
There is a research on the small-scale module of the nuclear reactors to be used in the data center,
to be used in some industrial gardens.
We think that in the following 30 years, we have to pay attention to the small scale and
safety nuclear models to be connected to the data center for some consumption.
So this is also a very attractive technology.
So the next one is that the comprehensive energy system, how to operate, how to optimization,
how to planning, so this is also a very important problem for the new power system.
Because the user not only needs electricity, but also needs heat and needs cooling energy.
And this energy, almost all of this energy comes from the electricity.
So the operation control and optimize the scheduling of the integrated energy system
is very important for the power systems.
And we have to design optimal dynamic allocation planning by the market based on the market.
So we have to think how to run such an integrated energy system with very high efficiency and very low price.
And the last one is the market.
The market-driven optimization of the energy resource allocation and regulation operation.
because we cannot regulate, we cannot change the regulation of the qualified
problem. We have no change, we have no regulation. What it means is that if we use the storage, and how can we operate the storage based on the reasonable market system mechanism.
So we have to improve the market level electricity market to promote for the
four participants of the renewable energy to exploit the capacity of the compensation
mechanism and the capacity market and to improve the response mechanism of the demand-side
resources so this depends on the policy of the common policy we have to issue a lot of new
policies to encourage the user to take part in the regulation of the power and also we have to
strengthen the collaboration of the electricity and the carbon market to
improve the carbon price depending to strengthen the connection between the
carbon the green energy and the green certification market to reflect the
market value of the emission reduction so the carbon is also very important
factor to affect the new power system operation.
So, we have quickly acquired the third part,
the application technology for the new power system.
The one kind of new applied technology is forecast.
For the source, for the generation forecast,
and for the distribution load forecast,
and also for the weather forecast.
So based on the precise forecast that we can operate the power system.
So this is one thing.
Another one is how we can plan, how we can make optimization of the configuration of the new power system.
This is the second one, the ordinary one.
Second one, application technology.
And the third one is how to control, how to make optimal control,
to make an optimum dispatching of a new kind of power system.
We have a lot of methods to do some operations.
And the third one is for the service.
To use the service to serve the user, serve the customer,
for their, for example, temperature, for their maintenance,
for the equipment maintenance for the low-carbon measures and so on.
We have to make a service for the high efficiency of the handling use for the users.
We have to make an accelerated service for the power grid, for the frequency adjustment,
for example, the voltage adjustment, the peak load adjustment and so on.
So I think we think that the advance of patient service is also very important for the key application technologies for the power system.
And we have to design the comprehensive demand response scheme for the multi-energy collaboration.
So this is dependent on the policy, on the various of the system to encourage the user to take part in the new power system operation.
And we have to make data awareness from the lower level of voltage.
For example, we have to make a deep resection, a deep resection of the operation status,
especially for the low voltage state.
For example, in the 10 kW voltage, we have less awareness, we have less collection of data.
Especially for the 380 volts, for the low voltage network, we have less means to collect data.
to awareness of the operation situations of the network.
Also, the last one is the market, how to operate, how to trade, how to make the reasonable mechanism of the market.
This is also a very important technology.
We think that through the large kind of pay application on technologies, we can also change
the operation.
We can change the, we can also make the optimal operation of the process.
Well, the time is over.
Any questions?
Please feel free to raise questions.
Don't be nervous.
I have a lot, but I have to think about it.
I understand that you have about more than 50% of renewable energy in the system in Thailand coming from solar and wind.
So with this 50% and you have already a lot of development,
And how do you solve this challenge?
How do we reduce the development and are we able to increase the renewable energy for solar and wind power?
Okay, it's a good problem.
I have already told you that from 2016 to 2020, we have opened an expert group to discuss, to study the future of Chinese politics.
We have forecast that by 2050, we will build about half of the power percentage of the
renewable energy, the wind power and solar power, to be connected into the power system.
But nowadays the government has already ahead of the schedule.
This planning has to be in 2035, maybe in the next 10 years, we will come to more than half of the renewable energy.
But how to operate it?
Now that we have summarized a lot of technologies, the state grid has issued a lot of research projects to make the dispatching center to be reformed.
Just as what I said, we have reformed the dispatching order from 15 minutes.
We just reduce the interview orders of the control manners from 15 minutes maybe to 10 minutes, to 5 minutes, to 1 minute.
So that as the control period becomes shorter and shorter, I think the control process will become more regulated.
So this is one method.
Another method is that so the storage is not enough nowadays.
It's not enough to balance, to compare with the liberties.
And the third means that we have to make a reform,
make a reform of the traditional coal-fired power plants.
We make the power plants, we cannot reduce,
we cannot cancel the coal-fired power plants.
We gradually reduce the carburant output, but the carburant cannot stop operation.
If we reduce the output, the efficiency will become lower.
So we have to take part in a lot of transformation
transformation, to make the reduced electrical covalent compounds to produce steam, to heat
some material, to make a heat storage. So this is a big plan for the Chinese generation
group. So we use the three methods to make the high percentage of the operation stable
and optimized. Any questions?
Hi, my name is Sebastian. I come from Chile. I would like to know your thoughts about the
hydrogen technology. Do you think it will be used for what and in which magnitude? And
the other one is, is China considering this technology for coal-fired power plants to
in order to capture and sequestration of their emissions.
You mean the hydropower?
No, hydrogen.
Hydrogen, oh, hydrogen.
Yeah, maybe in last meeting,
we have organized many famous experts
to discuss about the story.
And most of the experts think that
without hydrogen production,
the new power system cannot be achieved.
So the ultimate measure of the consumption of the renewable energy is to produce the hydrogen.
And when the electrical power tariffs become lower and lower,
When the concentrated renewable energy, for example, wind power, wind farm and PV farms,
and they generate energy power, it cannot transfer to the east.
They have to produce, they have to consume the countryside, so the only means is to produce
hydrogen.
But nowadays, the price of hydrogen production and transportation is relatively high.
We think that maybe 10 years or 20 years later, the hydrogen technology will become normal.
And this is why we think that the hydrogen is the ultimate means of the storage for the new power systems.
Hello, I am from the Philippines.
You have mentioned that you are trying to grow the share of renewable energy to your power units.
It will come at the expense of coal, so the higher the R.E. share, the lower will be the share of coal.
What is your policy that will stop the share of coal in terms of your power generation?
Because, just to give context, in the Philippines, you have this coal moratorium for greenfield coal power plants.
So, it limits the construction of new coal power plants.
But it allows the operation of old power plants that came into operation before the issuance of the moratorium.
You have a similar policy that is being implemented in China.
You mean the policy?
Yes.
The policy from the government department
to encourage the users to use the radio benefit?
Yeah, yeah.
But I don't know how about the profile
power plant, the territory power plant.
Maybe the ratio for the coil profile power plant
relatively lower than the radio benefit.
But in China, the coal price become higher.
I think the coal maybe produce a lot of food, so the prices become higher.
So the coal-fired power plants, so everything that renewable energy,
the price of it in the future, 10 or 20 years,
the price of the renewable energy is reduced to 0.2.
Thank you for your lecture just now.
I'm Aisha from Malaysia.
here i would like to ask about the power reliability in china just now you show us the
the comparison between the china and the other developed country in the power reliability and
so by integrating a battery energy storage system to the system how does it improve the
power reliability and also how do you compare the lithium-ion battery
technology with the flow batteries technology?
You think that's to increase the reliability?
Yeah.
Yeah, but notice reliability has no price in China because we think that the policy
will encourage the power utility to make high price with the high quality of the electricity.
So this is a reasonable price system, but in China we have to promote the government to make the policy.
I think that the story can make the power quality, change the power quality, but it depends on the policy.
We have a price, we have a price for the voltage level, we have a price for the frequency,
because if the boot level and frequency is not meet the requirement of the user, they will be punished.
But there is no punishment for the reliability in China.
So we think that is the shortage of the policy.
No question?
Okay, thank you for your attention.
Thank you.
Thank you Professor Zhang Guoyang for your exciting lecture.
Ladies and gentlemen, it is now time for an offer break.
Please take a short rest.